hikarabita kotoba wo tsunai de
connecting old words that have been used up
soredemo bokura shinpuru na omoi wo tsutaetai dake na no
I just want to convey my simple thoughts
fukinukeru kusunda ano hi no kaze wa
that day's faint wind blows away
kinou no haikyo ni uchi sutete
at the castle ruins of yesterday
kimi to warau ima wo ikiru no da
I'll laugh with you and live for the moment
soredemo ano dekigoto ga kimi wo kurushimeru daro
still that incident will continue to trouble you, right?
dakarakoso sayonara nanda
that's why it must be good-bye
konomama nanimo nokorazu ni anata to wakachiau dake
leaving nothing behind, let us share what is left
yagate bokura wa sore ga subetee dato kigatsuite
in time, we'll realize that it was everything
kanashimi wa hoo wo tsutatte namida no kawa ni naru dake
and sadness will touch our cheeks, creating a river of tears
yureru omoi wa tsuyoi uzu ni natte tokeau no yo
Trembling thoughts swept into a vortex and melting away
This is not good,
looks like a storm is coming.
What?
Idate...
Run Idate!
The Stormy Disturbance
of Nagi Island!!
Rokusho... Aoi!
I thought you had run away.
Wasn't running away
your specialty?
Shut up!
I'm different from you!
No, you are the same kind
of human as I am.
A betrayer who doesn't trust others.
Betraying your own brother,
walking away from the village,
and capable of thinking only of yourself.
The worst kind of man.
Such a man...
doesn't deserve to live!
Die!
Sakura, is your wound okay?
Uh-huh.
A wound like this is nothing.
But...
Those Rain Ninja... huh?
Yes.
Hah, they're nothing!
No, it's not that!
If they're headed towards Idate...
Oh! Idate is in danger!
That's what I've been saying!
Hey, Naruto!
This is no time to be playing around.
No!
They're here now.
Naruto!
Lucky us!
We are invincible in water.
Geez, what a troublesome guy.
They've now fallen into our trap.
Water Clone Jutsu!
Sakura!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
How stupid. What use can
Shadow Clones have in this situation?
There's no way they can defeat
our Water Clones in water.
Even if you try to trick us,
I'm hanging on to the real body
right here.
What are they trying to do?
N-No way!
What a whirlpool...
Chakra is intertwined in it!
Naruto... you...
This is the application
of the first step
in my training for
the Rasengan!
Sakura!
Sakura, hang in there!
Sakura! Just hang in there!
Come on! Sakura!
Sakura!
Pull yourself together! Sakura!
I-I guess... I've got... to... do it...
S-Sasuke....
I'd like it if Sasuke is the one to do...
the CPR...
S-Sakura...
What the hell are you doing, idiot!
Sasuke?
We don't have any time to spare.
We need to meet up with Idate.
Wait, Sasuke.
Hey... Don't leave me.
It's about time...
Fukusuke reaches Modoroki Shrine.
There's no chance for you
to win now.
You can't even run
or stand up now.
When that pain spreads
throughout your whole body,
you'll reach a different finish line.
The finish line of death.
What are you thinking of doing
with that dirty knife?
Don't touch it!
Looks like you still don't understand
your situation.
All you have to do is run away.
You have no right to even
the slightest bit of integrity.
Boss...
I'm sorry...
I couldn't keep...
the promise I made with you.
Idate!
You bastard!
damn, what a downpour.
Are you the boss of the Rain Ninja?!
Looks like it was too hard
a task for them.
Even if they were
the same Genin as you,
seems like the Hidden Leaf ones
are better.
This is terrible...
But can Genin-level Ninja
fight against me?
Shut up!
Above!
Humph... So that's your level, after all.
I'll use the same method
I used on Idate,
and send you to hell.
No need to waste my Chakra.
Sakura!
Th-These damned things...
Those are poisoned needles specially
made by the Hidden Rain Village.
They will send you to hell
in a few minutes,
no matter how strong you are.
Don't you look down on us! Bastard...!
Looks like Fukusuke has reached
Modoroki Shrine.
Die gasping.
It's a death
that fits you Genin brats well.
Is Wagarashi winning this one too?
Isn't there a God or Buddha
in this world?
I miss the old times when
Jirocho was in charge.
Terrible, terrible, I'm drenched.
You are amazing, Fukusuke.
Keep on running to the goal,
and make our Boss Wagarashi happy.
Watch it, you scum.
Who do you think you are talking to?
What?
My victory is already assured.
Let me relax for a while.
Bastard, think you're so hot?!
Cut it out...
Brother...
What if something goes wrong
during the race?
Who knows what our boss
will do to us.
All right.
Just wait and see.
damn, that bastard!
Naruto, Sasuke...
Take this.
Sakura... What's that?
Before leaving the Leaf Village,
Tsunade-sama handed this to me.
Take this with you.
I am sure it will come in handy.
Grandma Tsunade?
I think he'll recover
consciousness now.
Sasuke and Naruto,
you take this, too.
O-Okay.
Also, we'll be too cold here,
so we need to move somewhere else.
Brother!
Look! I've finally become
a Ninja, too!
I see...
I've got to become the best
in everything!
I'll train hard,
and complete lots of missions.
And I'll become a Chunin super fast.
Then after that, a Jonin.
I'm going to be like you, Brother!
I'm Idate, the Swift Runner
making headway in life.
Brother?
Listen Idate...
In the world of Shinobi,
there is something more important
than success or power.
Something more important?
Until you understand that,
it's too early for you to talk that way.
Oh!
He's conscious now.
Are you okay?
What happened to Aoi?!
He disappeared...
So that Rain Ninja is called Aoi?
Idate, do you know him?
He...
...was a teacher when
I was in the Leaf Village.
You... are from the Leaf Village?
Aoi... betrayed the Leaf Village
and became a Jonin of the Hidden Rain.
What the hell do you mean?
Not yet.
You have to rest a little more.
How is your hand there?
That hand...
You kept it clenched all this time.
damn! I'd come all this way,
and yet I...!
It's too early to give up!
And you tell us that you were once
a Shinobi of the Leaf?!
I forgot all about the Leaf...
the moment
I walked away from the village.
You walked away from the village?
I was depressed after failing
the first test of the Chunin Exam.
That was close, Idate...
Don't take it so hard.
There are ways to become
a Chunin other than the Chunin Exam.
Really?!
Yes, really.
Just do as I tell you.
Okay!
Aoi-sensei...
Idate...
Aoi-sensei,
I'd brought them as you told me to.
All right.
These are indeed the Scroll of Sealing
and the legendary blade,
the Blade of the Thunder God, believed to
have been used by the Second Hokage.
Well done, Idate.
Now I can become a Chunin, right?
Sure you can...
in the Village Hidden in the Rain.
You are leaving
the Leaf together with me,
taking these as gifts to them.
But...
Of course.
There's no way you can get away with
stealing the village's treasures.
You tricked me!
To survive in this world,
you must not believe in others...
Remember that.
Well, what are you going to do, Idate?
Either way, you are already
a Rogue Ninja.
You'll be chained in jail for life,
if you are lucky.
Ever since then,
I haven't returned to the village.
I am an irresponsible man
who can't do a single thing right.
But Boss Jirocho believed in me.
Even though I'd never
been of any use to him.
Boss Jirocho had faith in me!
And yet, I...!
He's...
He's... like the old me...
No one will ever accept you!
Die Naruto!
Duck down, Naruto!
I'm... a worthless guy...
W-Why?
Because we are the same.
He's like me of the old days.
I go around and around,
and get nowhere...
I can't do anything right.
Aoi is right.
I have... no right to live...
You idiot!
There's a person
who still trusts you, right?
I know, Naruto.
You felt alone...
and you were suffering!
One is enough!
The race isn't over yet!
You never know how things will turn out
unless you try until the very end.
But...
Stand up now!
Naruto, it's not possible!
Idate's body is still...
If he can't run,
then I'll carry him on my back and run!
The opponent must already be
in Modoroki Shrine...
Don't give up!
Hey... Naruto...
Sasuke...
Let's leave it to Naruto here.
Jirocho is waiting for you, right?
Pull yourself together!
Boss, don't you think
he actually ran away?
He'll come.
I believe in Idate!
If you run away now,
you'll be a loser for your entire life!
For the people who believe
in you and wait for you...
It's the fastest boat around here.
I'm grateful.
No problem.
Edged tools aren't
for hurting people...
Show them what you've got!
Naruto! Please take me there!
All right. Leave it to me!
GET UP aa sumimasen
get up! oh, I'm sorry
goku tama ni boku tama ni
once in a long while, once in a while
yume ni yabureru hito no kakera ga
the remnants of a person broken by dreams
yama no you ni mieru
Iook like a mountain
kamisama ni hotokesama ni
clinging to God, clinging to Buddha
sugari naiteru hito no kakera ga
the remnants of a person crying
yama no you ni mieru
Iook like a mountain
danran dansu de RANDEBUU
rendezvous with a happy dance circle
ore shouri no poozu da randaran
this is my victory pose, round and around
SHEIKU SHEIKU SHEIKU sagasou janai
shake shake shake let's look
owaranai baibai no RIZUMU de
with a bye-bye rhythm that never ends
yama no you ni mieru
Iook like a mountain
Hey you!
What're you jabbering about,
lecturing like you're something else?!
You are so annoying!
Come on, Idate.
Boss Jirochi is waiting for you
at the finish line, right?
I don't care if this guy
is a Jonin or whatever.
I'm gonna beat him and make for
the finish line with all my might!
Next time:
"Just Before the Goal! The Fierce Battle of Roaring Thunder."